

Kuldip Patel

- C/707, Victory Sunrise,
 Opp. Vishwas City-7,
 Gota, Ahmedabad-382481
- (F) +91- 7069789414
- ilukaha@gmail.com
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/kuldip-patel-654a18b9

Experience

• Zydus Research Centre, Ahmedabad, Gujarat

Period: Sep 2017 to till date

Role: Senior Scientific Assistant

Department: Bioanalytical

Responsibility: Sample Preparation using different techniques,

LC-MS/MS Operation (API 3200, API 4000), HPLC Calibration, Method Development, Method Validation and Study sample analysis.

• Veeda Clinical Research LTD, Ahmedabad, Gujarat

Period: Nov 2015 to Sep 2017

Role: Research Associate

Department: Bioanalytical

Responsibility: Sample Preparation using different techniques,

LC-MS/MS Operation (API 5500), HPLC Calibration, Method Development, Method Validation and Study sample analysis, Method development and validation of large molecules i.e. Insulin

• Kiri Laboratories, Ahmedabad, Gujarat

Period: Jun 2015 to Nov 2015



Role: PMT Executive

Department: PMT

Responsibilities: Responsible for training of the pharmaceutical

marketing personnel. Responsible for joint working with

marketing person in field.

Education

• Bachelor of Pharmacy

Atmiya Pharmacy College, Vadodara affiliated to Gujarat Technological University, Gujarat

CGPA: 7.09

• Master of Pharmacy in Pharmaceutical Management and Regulatory Affairs

Atmiya Pharmacy College, Vadodara affiliated to Gujarat

Technological University, Gujarat

CGPA: 7.45

Professional Summary

Skilled Researcher enthusiastic about supporting advancements in bioanalysis. Passionate about increasing knowledge to drive growth and needed improvements. Ready to apply knowledge and 6 years of experience in research.

Skills

- Method Development
- Good Laboratory Practice
- Multidisciplinary team collaboration
- Basic computer and internet
- Handling of Analyst software Version 1.6.1, 1.6.2 and 1.7.1
- Troubleshooting for minor errors during handling of LC-MS/MS



Trainings and Certificates

Basic Training of LC-MS/MS

Period: 3 Days (Dec 2017)

Institute: Sciex centre, Gurgaon, India

Topic: Basic Application, Tuning, Mechanism Of Instrument,

Troubleshooting of LC-MS/MS

• Laboratory Quality Management System & Internal Audit As Per IS/ISO/IEC 17025:2017

Period: 4 Days (04/11/19 to 07/11/19)

Institute: National Institute of Training For Standardization, Bureau of Indian Standards conducted In-house at Zydus Research Centre, Cadila Healthcare Limited, Ahmedabad

Topic:

- ➤ Introduction to the course & laboratory accreditation: International perspective and basic definitions (LMS1)
- ➤ General requirement, structure & resources (LMS 2)
- ➤ ISO/IEC-17025 Process requirement (LMS 3)
- ➤ ISO/IEC-17025 Management system requirement (LMS 4)
- ➤ Risk based approach (LMS 5)
- ➤ Internal audit (LMS 6)
- ➤ NABL accreditation programme/route to accreditation (LMS 7)
- ➤ BIS LRS (LMS-8)
- > Discussion on case studies /evaluation exercise



Publication

"Estimation of ZYKR1 in human urine and plasma utilizing LC-MS/MS positive electrospray ionization; a kappa opioid receptor (KOR) agonist" in Journal of Chromatography B, Available at science direct

Languages

- English
- Hindi
- Gujarati

Personal Details

• Date of Birth: 09/10/1990

• Gender: Male

Declaration

I hereby declare that, the details furnished above are true an correct to the best of my knowledge and belief and i undertake t update of any changes therein.

